



lablnet01@gmail.com



+923405425178



Lane no 03 House No 09 razzaq town, Rawalpindi, Pakistan



29 June, 2001



github.com/Lablnet

LANGUAGE



Urdu

SKILL

Project Manager

Expert

PHP, PHP frameworks, CSS, HTML

Expert

Bootstrap / Materializecss

Very Good

MYSQL/Mariadb

Very Good

C,C++ and perl

Good

Computer Science good in SDLC and DevOps

Good

Security Adviser

Good

Electron Js, JavaScript/Jquery and python

Beginner

C# and Java

Learning

INTERESTS

Physics

Chemistry

Muhammad Umer Farooq

Computer Engineer

After spending three years in modern development i confidently say that I am how expert in PHP. I like to building every type projects that user interested, I also like building Frameworks and working on programming language. I even implemented my own extensible framework (ZestFramework). I am good at achieving any type of web development, user experience design, responsive web design, software writing and algorithm implementation.

EDUCATION

SSC i-ii

F G Boys Secondary School Westridge 1, RWP

05/2007 - 04/2017

HSSC i-ii

Punjab College of commerce

08/2017 - 04/2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

Creator and Founder

Zest Framework

04/2018 - Present

Zest is a simple yet powerful PHP MVC framework for rapid application development that is suited for small to large scale apps and APIs.

Software Engineer

WRH

08/2018 – Present An Academy website

Senior Backend Developer

Utang Tech

03/2018 - 08/2018

https://www.utangsocial.com/ http://utangtransport.com/ They closed their business(flopped)

CERTIFICATES

PGC Coding Hunt Certificate (02/2018 – Present)

C++ coding competition by punjab group of colleges

PHP Classes Certificate (04/2018 - Present)

https://www.phpclasses.org/browse/author/1465021.html